Inventory of the Colby E. "Babe" Slater Collection D-394
University of California, Davis General Library, Dept. of Special Collections
- Publications, 1912-2004; Series 3; 23 folders.
  - Travel, 1913, undated; Subseries 3.5; 6 folders.
    - Berner Oberland. Zurich: Wehrli A. G., undated; D394.3.5.2; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Bern (Switzerland: Canton) -- Pictorial works; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
    - Handy Guide to Brussels and its Environs. Brussels, undated; D394.3.5.3; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Brussels (Belgium) -- Guidebooks; Brussels (Belgium) -- Description and travel; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
    - Nouvelle Carte de France. Paris: A. Taride, undated; D394.3.5.4; 1 map (Box IV, Folder Drawer S)
    - Relief Panorama of the Rhine. Cologne (Germany): Hoursch & Bechstedt, undated; D394.3.5.5; 1 map (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Rhine River Valley -- Description and travel; Rhine River -- Pictorial works; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
    - Souvenir from Brussels: 24 Photos with Explanations in French and in English, undated; D394.3.5.6; 1 volume (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Brussels (Belgium) -- Pictorial works; Brussels (Belgium) -- Description and travel; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
  - Yolo County (Calif.), 1922-2004; Subseries 3.6; 3 folders
    Arranged chronologically. Contains clippings.
    - Clippings, American Legion, Woodland (Calif.), football team, 1923, 1927; D394.3.6.1 (Box 6, Folder 10.1)
      Headline banner.
      Football -- California -- Yolo County; Football teams -- California -- Yolo County; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; American Legion. Post 77 (Yolo County (Calif.)
      - Clipping, Woodland wins Legion game, undated; D394.3.6.1.1 (Box 6, Folder 10.2)
      - Clipping, Legion grid football game at Kezar today: Woodland and Chico will start battle at 2 o'clock this afternoon, December 4, 1927; D394.3.6.1.2 (Box 6, Folder 10.3)
      - Clipping, Woodland's grid title protested by Arbuckle, undated; D394.3.6.1.3 (Box 6, Folder 10.4)
        Football teams -- California -- Yolo County; Football teams -- California -- Yolo County; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; American Legion. Post 77 (Yolo County (Calif.)
      - Clipping, Legion gridders battle tomorrow: Merced favored slightly over Woodland in championship argument at Kezar Stadium, undated; D394.3.6.1.4 (Box 6, Folder 10.5)
      - Clippings, 5,000 fans watch 6-0 grid battle: Merced Yellowjackets lose out in ex-service men's state championship contest, undated; D394.3.6.1.5 (Box 6, Folder 10.6)
      - Clipping, Woodland American Legion team in titular tilt today, undated; D394.3.6.1.6 (Box 6, Folder 10.7)
      - Clipping, Trains, stage to take fans to big game; Babe Slater: when the Vets have their back to the wall, the stands call for 'Babe', undated; D394.3.6.1.7 (Box 6, Folder 10.8)
      - Clipping, Woodland Legion cops state gridiron title: Yolo County grid team vanquishes Merced opponents, December 5, 1927; D394.3.6.1.8 (Box 6, Folder 10.9)
      - Clipping, Woodland Legion beats Merced 6-0, undated; D394.3.6.1.9 (Box 6, Folder 10.10)
      - Clipping, Sports: Slater will start against Merced; Spillman, flashy half-back, lost to Veterans, undated; D394.3.6.1.10 (Box 6, Folder 10.11)
      - Clipping, Sports: Vets' all-around play proves too much for Yellowjackets' stars, undated; D394.3.6.1.11 (Box 6, Folder 10.12)
      - Clipping, Sports: Woodland conquers Merced, 6 to 0, in championship battle; Babe downs set world's record; Slater leave's before banquet, undated; D394.3.6.1.12 (Box 6, Folder 10.13)
      - Clipping, Woodland Daily Democrat, November 30, 1923; D394.3.6.1.13 (Box 6, Folder 10.14)
      - Clipping, 50 years ago ... 1927, December 13, 1977; D394.3.6.1.14 (Box 6, Folder 10.15)
      - Clipping, 50 years ago ... 1927, December 17, 1977; D394.3.6.1.15 (Box 6, Folder 10.16)
      - Clipping, 50 years ago ... 1927: Babe Slater's last quarter touchdown run of two yards gave the Woodland American Legion team a 6-2 victory over Willows, undated; D394.3.6.1.16 (Box 6, Folder 10.17)
      - Clipping, 50 years ago ... 1927: Woodland's American Legion football team trounced Grass Valley 30-0 before 100 fans at Beamer Park, undated; D394.3.6.1.17 (Box 6, Folder 10.18)
      - Clipping, Untitled, undated; D394.3.6.18 (Box 6, Folder 10.19)
        Scrap or detached portion of article about California Rugby team.
        Rugby football; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
      - Clipping, Woodland legion eleven wins, undated; D394.3.6.1.19 (Box 6, Folder 10.20)
      - Envelope, Merced-Woodland write-ups, undated; D394.3.6.1.20 (Box 6, Folder 10.21)
        Small, empty envelope with words handwritten in ink on front.
    - Conway Ranch, Woodland (Calif.), D394.3.6.2 (Box 6, Folder 11.1)
      - Clipping, Football stars are successful ranchers, undated; D394.3.6.2.1 (Box 6, Folder 11.2)
        Ranching -- California -- Yolo County; Ranch life -- California.; Sheep ranches -- California.; Slater, Colby E. -- Arcive; Conway Ranch (Woodland, Calif.)
      - Clipping, County can't afford to lose these 2 men, 1924; D394.3.6.2.2 (Box 6, Folder 11.3)
        Ranching -- California -- Yolo County; Ranch life -- California.; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Conway Ranch (Woodland, Calif.)
      - Clipping, Long bridge built to save marooned sheep, December 14, 1922; D394.3.6.2.3 (Box 6, Folder 11.4)
        Ranching -- California -- Yolo County; Sheep ranches -- California.; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Conway Ranch (Woodland, Calif.)
      - Clipping, Long, temporary bridge saves flock of sheep, December 15, 1922; D394.3.6.2.4 (Box 6, Folder 11.5)
      - Clipping, Rush to save band of 2300 marooned sheep, December 13, 1922; D394.3.6.2.5 (Box 6, Folder 11.6)
      - Clipping, 9468 Infected, undated; D394.3.6.2.6 (Box 6, Folder 11.7)
    - Clippings, Clarksburg (Calif.), [1924]; D394.3.6.3 (Box 6, Folder 11.8)
      - Clipping, Slater buys 100 acres Clarksburg, undated; D394.3.6.3.1 (Box 6, Folder 11.9)
        Clarksburg (Calif.) -- History; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
      - Clipping, Demotion foolishness, undated; D394.3.6.3.2 (Box 6, Folder 11.10)
        Clarksburg (Calif.) -- History; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Rotary Club of Sacramento
      - Clipping, Delta bill approved by Clarksburg farm group, February 15, 1929; D394.3.6.3.3 (Box 6, Folder 11.11)
      - Clipping, 50 years ago--1927: Clarksburg high school will start operation for the first time next month, August 26, 1977; D394.3.6.3.4 (Box 6, Folder 11.12)
      - Clipping, 25 years ago--1950: C.E. (Babe) Slater, Clarksburg farmer, was elected president of the county rural fire protection association, undated; D394.3.6.3.5 (Box 6, Folder 11.13)
        Clarksburg (Calif.) -- History; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Yolo County Rural Fire Protection Association (Yolo County, Calif.)
      - Clipping, 10 years ago--1965: Services were held for Colby E. (Babe) Slater, 68, Clarksburg farmer and one of Yolo County's all-time outstanding athletes, undated; D394.3.6.3.6 (Box 6, Folder 11.14)
        Clarksburg (Calif.) -- History; Death notices; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
      - Clipping, Slater: In Clarksburg, January 32, 1965, Colby E. Slater, husband of Mrs. Virginia C. Slater of Clarksburg ..., D394.3.6.3.7 (Box 6, Folder 11.15)
        Death notices; Clarksburg (Calif.) -- History; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
      - Clipping, Babe Slater dies of heart attack, 1965; D394.3.6.3.8 (Box 6, Folder 11.16)
        Obituaries; Clarksburg (Calif.) -- History; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
      - Clipping, Colby Slater funeral is set for tomorrow, 1965; D394.3.6.3.9 (Box 6, Folder 11.17)
        Two copies
      - Clipping, Probate notice no. 16551: Notice of the time and place for hearing the petition to probate the last will and testament of Colby E. Slater, 1965; D394.3.6.3.10 (Box 6, Folder 11.18)
        Decedents' estates; Clarksburg (Calif.) -- History; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
      - Clipping, Slater estate petition filed, 1965; D394.3.6.3.11 (Box 6, Folder 11.19)
      - Clipping, Yoloan's estate distributed: Judge James C. McDermott granted a final distribution of the Colby E. (Babe) Slater estate in probate court Thursday, November 1966; D394.3.6.3.12 (Box 6, Folder 11.20)
      - Clipping, $23,593 Estate listed: the late Colby E. Slater, who died in Yolo County on January 30, 1965, left a partial estate valued at $23,593.67, an inventory and appraisement in the estate, filed yesterday, shows, 1966; D394.3.6.3.13 (Box 6, Folder 11.21)
    - Yolo County Rural Fire Protection Association, D394.3.6.4 (Box 6, Folder 11.22)
      - Clipping, New officers, Four of the newly elected officers of the Rural Fire Protection association of Yolo County ... are shown, undated; D394.3.6.4.1 (Box 6, Folder 11.23)
        Fire societies (cooperative societies) -- California -- Yolo County; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Yolo County Rural Fire Protection Association (Yolo County, Calif.)
      - Clipping, Visiting editors: nine foreign newspaper editors were guests of the annual demonstration and inspection of the Yolo County Fire Protection Association Saturday, undated; D394.3.6.4.2 (Box 6, Folder 11.24)
      - Clipping, 10 years ago--1950, undated; D394.3.6.4.3 (Box 6, Folder 11.25)
      - [Handwritten note], 1950; D394.3.6.4.4 (Box 6, Folder 11.39)
        Fire societies (cooperative societies) -- California -- Yolo County; Slater, Colby E. -- Archives; Yolo County Rural Fire Protection Association (Yolo County, Calif.)
    - Clippings, Yolo County Farm Bureau (Calif.), 1952; D394.3.6.5 (Box 6, Folder 11.26)
      - Clipping, C.E. Slater again heads Farm Bureau, January 14, 1952; D394.3.6.5.1 (Box 6, Folder 11.27)
        Farmers -- California -- Yolo County.; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Yolo County Farm Bureau (Yolo County, Calif.)
      - Clipping, C.E. Slater heads Farm Bureau; Mrs. Lester Holmes reelected; 530 attend Farm Bureau bean feed, January 15, 1951; D394.3.6.5.2 (Box 6, Folder 11.28)
      - Clipping, Highlights of the big F.B. fete: annual 'bean feed' is again a gala event, January 14, 1952; D394.3.6.5.3 (Box 6, Folder 11.29)
      - Clipping, To the winner: C.E. (Babe) Slater, left, Yolo County Farm Bureau president, 1952; D394.3.6.5.4 (Box 6, Folder 11.30)
      - Clipping, Yolo delegation of 35 are attending national meet of Farm Bureau Federation: begins Sunday in Seattle, undated; D394.3.6.5.5 (Box 6, Folder 11.31)
      - Clipping, Yolo farmers retain chief; Honor 4H boy, 1952; D394.3.6.5.6 (Box 6, Folder 11.32)
        Original and copy. Two copies of illustration.
      - Clipping, Yolo farmers retain chief, cite boy for 4H Club work, 1952; D394.3.6.5.7 (Box 6, Folder 11.33)
      - Clipping, Getting ready for the 1958 March of Dimes in the East Yolo area are C.C. (Babe) Slater (left), community chairman for the Clarksburg area, D394.3.6.5.8 (Box 6, Folder 11.34)
      - Clipping, 25 years ago--1951: C.E. (Babe) Slater of Clarksburg was elected president of Yolo County Farm Bureau, January 22, 1976; D394.3.6.5.9 (Box 6, Folder 11.35)
      - Clipping, 25 years ago--1952: C.E. Slater (Babe) Slater of Clarksburg was reelected president of Yolo County Farm Bureau, January 21, 1977; D394.3.6.5.10 (Box 6, Folder 11.36)
      - Clipping, 50 years ago--1954: Ten Yolo County Farm Bureau members will sail from New York April 2, March 23, 2004; D394.3.6.5.11 (Box 6, Folder 11.37)
      - Clipping, C.E. Slater, new Yolo County Farm Bureau president, [1951?]; D394.3.6.5.12 (Box 6, Folder 11.38)
        Farmers -- California -- Yolo County.; Slater, Colby E.; Yolo County Farm Bureau (Yolo County, Calif.)
    - Clippings, Woodland (Calif.) Athletic Hall of Fame, 1973; D394.3.6.6 (Box 6, Folder 12.1)
      - Clipping, First Woodland Hall of Fame banquet June 14: 'Babe' Slater--'prince of good fellows', May 18, 1973; D394.3.6.6.1 (Box 6, Folder 12.2)
        Four copies.
        Olympic athletes -- United States; Rugby football; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Woodland Athletic Hall of Fame (Woodland, Calif.)
      - Clipping, First Woodland Hall of Famers inducted: Steward, Putnam selected athletes-of-the-year, June 15, 1973; D394.3.6.6.2 (Box 6, Folder 12.3)
        Sports -- History -- 20th century; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Woodland Athletic Hall of Fame (Woodland, Calif.)
      - Clipping, Hall of Famers finds permanent home, January 28, 1976; D394.3.6.6.3 (Box 6, Folder 12.4)
      - Clipping, Woodland High football coach for 27 seasons: Palmer Muhl--'Sundown; meant success, June 5, 1973; D394.3.6.6.4 (Box 6, Folder 12.5)
      - Clipping, Gloria Jacobs Norton, 13 world records: she would make Annie Oakley hunt a hole, May 24, 1973; D394.3.6.6.5 (Box 6, Folder 12.6)
        Sports -- History -- 20th century; Slater, Colby E.; Woodland Athletic Hall of Fame (Woodland, Calif.); Norton, Gloria J.
      - Clipping, Immortal 'Babe' in Hall of Fame, June 12, 1973; D394.3.6.6.6 (Box 6, Folder 12.7)
        Sports -- History -- 20th century; Rugby football; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Woodland Athletic Hall of Fame (Woodland, Calif.)
      - Clipping, Sports: 1927 Legionnaires, state grid champs; Unbeaten Vets beat Merced 6-0 in Kezar stadium for crown:, June 12, 1973; D394.3.6.6.7 (Box 6, Folder 12.8)
      - Clipping, Sports: 'Buck' Baily, builder of champions; fundamentalist coached Wolves' A-B-C-D teams, June 6, 1973; D394.3.6.6.8 (Box 6, Folder 12.9)
        Sports -- History -- 20th century; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Woodland Athletic Hall of Fame (Woodland, Calif.); Bailey, Carrol
      - Clipping, Linn Farish, at best in '24 Olympic finals: scores two tries against French, WWII medal winner, May 29, 1973; D394.3.6.6.9 (Box 6, Folder 12.10)
        Sports -- History -- 20th century; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Farish, Linn M. (Linn Markley ), 1901-1944; Woodland Athletic Hall of Fame (Woodland, Calif.)
      - Clipping, Yerman surprises in trials, wins gold, May 22, 1973; D394.3.6.6.10 (Box 6, Folder 12.11)
        Sports -- History -- 20th century; Woodland Athletic Hall of Fame (Woodland, Calif.); Yerman, Jack
  - Other Subjects, 1912-1950; Subseries 3.7; 1 folder.
    Contains clippings that relate to various rugby teams including Berkeley (Calif.) High School and the New Zealand All Blacks.
    - Clipping, Berkeley's superior heft carries team to victory, undated; D394.3.7.1 (Box 6, Folder 13.1)
      High School sports -- California; Rugby football; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive
    - Clipping, Flattering rugby win for Scots, undated; D394.3.7.2 (Box 6, Folder 13.2)
    - Clipping, Scots beat France at Inverleith, January 26, 1925; D394.3.7.3 (Box 6, Folder 13.3)
    - Clipping, America wins from British rugby stars: fast plays feature American--British rugby game for charity, undated; D394.3.7.4 (Box 6, Folder 13.4)
    - Clipping, Daily sketch: France trounced by Scotland, January 26, 1925; D394.3.7.5 (Box 6, Folder 13.5)
    - Clipping, Poet's birthplace, undated; D394.3.7.6 (Box 6, Folder 13.6)
      Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; Burns, Robert, 1759-1796
    - Clipping, "We know how to lose"--the Prince: New Zealand footballers always welcome, undated; D394.3.7.7 (Box 6, Folder 13.7)
      Rugby football; Rugby football teams -- New Zealand; Slater, Colby E. -- Archive; All Blacks (Rugby team)
    - Clipping, Great send-off: All Blacks mobbed by London crowds, undated; D394.3.7.8 (Box 6, Folder 13.8)
    - Clipping, Prince's souvenir: autographed cards sent to the All Blacks, undated; D394.3.7.9 (Box 6, Folder 13.9)
    - Clipping, Probably there has never been in the history of this country so notable a gathering of sporting and athletic folk as those who at the Piccadilly yesterday attended the "farewell lunch given by the sportsmen of the Motherland to the All Blacks, undated; D394.3.7.10 (Box 6, Folder 13.10)
    - Clipping, Varsity takes third game from Titans, 1914; D394.3.7.11 (Box 6, Folder 13.11)
    - Clipping, France fails at Inverleith: Scotland claims big victory with unsatisfactory display, January 26, 1925; D394.3.7.12 (Box 6, Folder 13.12)
    - Central California farm review (Modesto, Calif.), June 2, 1949; D394.3.7.13 (Box 6, Folder 13.13)
    - Elmhurst-Brookfield journal, November 10, 1949; D394.3.7.14 (Box 6, Folder 13.14)
    - Neighborhood journal, September 14, 1950; D394.3.7.15 (Box 6, Folder 13.15)
- Ephemera, 1917-1980; Series 4; 30 folders.
  Arranged by subject in the following subseries: University of California, Davis; World War I; Seventh Olympic Games; Eighth Olympic Games; Travel; and Yolo County (Calif.). Contains cards, certificates, diplomas, fliers, lists, a menu, postcards, a poster, a print, programs, a receipt, stickers, and tickets.
  - University of California, Davis, 1917-1980; Subseries 4.1; 4 folders.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Flyer, Picnic Day, April 28, 1917; D394.4.1.1; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Program, Picnic Day, April 28, 1917; D394.4.1.2; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letterhead, Picnic Day, 1917; D394.4.1.3; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 2A)
    - Diploma, May 18, 1917; D394.4.1.4 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Program, Cal Aggies Athletic Hall of Fame, Oct. 10, 1980; D394.4.1.5 (Box 2, Folder 4.1)
    - Letter from James H. Meyer announcing the 1980 University of California, Davis, Athletic Hall of Fame inductees, September 16, 1980; D394.4.1.6; 2 Leaves (Box 2, Folder 4.2)
    - Suggested wording of Colby E. "Babe" Slater's University of California, Davis, Athletic Hall of Fame plaque, undated; D394.4.1.7; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 4A)
  - Word War I, 1917-1919; Subseries 4.2; 3 folders
    - Certificate, registration, June 5, 1917; D394.4.2.1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Certificate, appointment to rank of corporal, United States Army, November 1, 1917; D394.4.2.2 (Box 7, Folder 1.1)
    - Certificate, Armed Forces service, November 11, 1919; D394.4.2.3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Certificate of gratitude, circa 1919; D394.4.2.4 (Box 7, Folder 1.2)
  - Seventh Olympic Games, Antwerp (Belgium), 1920; Subseries 4.3; 9 folders, 1 framed diploma.
    Includes cards, a certificate, an Olympic diploma, postcards, a print, stickers, programs, a poster, and tickets.
    - Cards, 1920; D394.4.3.1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Includes two identification cards (blank) from 1920 Olympic Games and a calling card of R. T. Belville, Ingenieur [engineer), Antwerp.
    - Certificate, United States Olympic Rugby Team, 1920; D394.4.3.2 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Olympic Diploma, 1920; D394.4.3.3 (Object Room 141, item 1)
    - Souvenir de la VII Olympiade, Anvers, 1920; D394.4.3.4; 10 postcards (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Equipe Nationale Des Etats Unis D'Amerique, Champions des Olumpiades d'Anvers [postcard], 1920; D394.4.3.5 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      Postcard depicting the 1920 United States Olympic Rugby team.
    - Print, United States Olympic Rugby Team, 1920; D394.4.3.6 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Olympic Stamps, 1920; 1924; D394.4.3.7 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Vll Olympiade (Anvers, Belgique), Programme General, July-September 1920; D394.4.3.8; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 13.1)
    - Grand Match de Rugby, Stade Toulousain contre American-Team [program], 26 Septembre 1920; D394.4.3.9; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 13.2)
    - Poster, September 1920; D394.4.3.8 (Box IV, Folder Drawer S, Box 13)
      A modern reproduction of this poster is in box 13.
    - Tickets, September-October 1920; D394.4.3.9 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Eighth Olympic Games, Paris, 1924-1925; Subseries 4.4; 3 folders, 1 framed diploma.
    Arranged chronologically. See also the Scrapbook series for additional ephemera.
    - Lists, "Friendship Fund", March 1924; D394.4.4.1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Olympic diploma, 1924; D394.4.4.2 (Object Room 141)
    - Menu, May 19, 1924; D394.4.4.3 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Flyer, United States Olympic Rugby Team on tour of British Columbia, Jan. 1, [1925]; D394.4.4.4 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Poster, 1924 (Case IV, Drawer S, Box 13)
  - Travel, undated; Subseries 4.5; 8 folders
    Contains ephemera related to travel in the following countries: Belgium, England, France, Germany, Holland, Ireland, Monaco, and Switzerland.
    - Postcards, undated; D394.4.5.1 (Box 2, Folder 17-23)
    - Stickers, various hotels, undated; D394.4.5.2 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Yolo County (Calif.), 1924-1973; Subseries 4.6; 3 folders
    - Certificate, March 20, 1924; D394.4.6.1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Receipt; membership dues for Woodland (Calif.); Lodge No. 1299; B.P.O. Elks, March 31, 1930; D394.4.6.2 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Program, Woodland (Calif.) Athletic Hall of Fame, June 14, 1974; D394.4.6.3 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Certificate of Colby E. "Babe" Slater's status as Senior Alumnus of the California Alumni Association, undated; D394.4.6.4 (Box 2, Folder 27A.1)
    - Postcard, 1965; D394.4.6.5 (Box 2, Folder 27A.2)
      "Olympic Club, Monday 27 Dec. 65. Roaring 20's Gang. R.S.V.P"
    - Memorial Card from Colby E. "Babe" Slater's funeral, 1965; D394.4.6.7 (Box 2, Folder 27A.3)
    - Memorial card containing Colby E. "Babe" Slater's Berkeley Daily Gazette obituary, 1965; D394.4.6.8 (Box 2, Folder 27A.4)
- Photographic Materials, 1906-1961; Series 5; 153 prints and 45 negatives.
  Arranged in two subseries: Photographic Prints and Negatives.
  - Photographic Prints, 1906-1961; Subseries 5.1; 153 prints.
    Arranged by subject. Contains many photographs of Babe Slater. The Berkeley (Calif.) High School Rugby Team prints include a group portrait and three action shots. Most of the University of California, Davis prints are of Picnic Day 1916. The World War I prints are snapshots of soldiers. The Seventh Olympic Games prints are formal shots of the United States Olympic Rugby Team and images from a rugby match between the Americans and the French Sud-Ouest Team at Bordeaux. Prints from the Eighth Olympic Games range from formal shots of the United States Olympic Rugby Team to snapshots of team members aboard ship. See also the Scrapbook series for more prints from the Eighth Olympic Games. Images of Slater, family, and friends from childhood through the later years make up the Family and Friends prints. Unidentified prints are snapshots of bridges, buildings, cattle, sporting events, and ships.
    - Berkeley (Calif.) High School Rugby Team, 1911-1912; D394.5.1.1; 4 prints. (Box 2, Folder 28-30, Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Oakland versus Berkeley, October 28, 1911; D394.5.1.1.1; 1 photographic print black and white 8 x 17 cm (Box 2, Folder 28)
        Berkeley High School Rugby Team
        "Oak 3, Berk 10. Slater [trying] to block a kick from the full-back of Oakland."
        Rugby football; Slater, Colby E.; University of California, Berkeley -- Pictorial works
      - Berkeley High School Rugby Team, circa 1911; D394.5.1.1.2; 1 photographic print black and white 9 x 15 cm (Box 2, Folder 29)
        "Norman Slater thinks these picures are taken on Cal campus (Berkeley). Brother [Norm] was [a] very good good rugby player - 1911 would have made Dad [Colby "Babe" Slater] pretty young. The one pic. identifies the Cal Berk field."
        [Explanatory Note by Marilyn Slater McCapes]
      - Berkeley High School "Ruggers" Team Photograph, 1912; D394.5.1.1.3; 1 photographic print black and white 13 x 18 cm (Box 2, Folder 30)
        "Top row: last man starting from left - first man starting from right: Babe Slater."
        Rugby football; Slater, Colby E.; Berkeley High School (Berkeley, Calif.) -- History
      - Berkeley High School Rugby Team, circa 1911; D394.5.1.1.4; 1 photographic print black and white 39 x 25 cm (Box 7, Folder 3)
        "High School years - Berkeley. Circa 1911. C.E. ["Babe"] Slater far right edge of photo. Brother Norm - not sure. Looks like Cal-Berkeley field again."
        [Explanatory note by Marilyn Slater McCapes]
    - University of California, Davis, 1915-1961; D394.5.1.2; 28 prints. (Box 2, Folder 31-55)